Dan Hubbard

Senior Product Manager

Full lifecycle Product Manager with a development background in digital agencies and consultancies. Broad experience across both startups and established products. Particular interest in product strategy and coaching/mentoring product managers.

A varied career history in consultancy means I'm adept in hitting the ground running in new roles and industries/domains, and have developed strong skills in stakeholder management and influence, including at senior levels.

dan@parachute.io

Fully remote, or flexible hybrid (London & South Coast)

Education

BSc Computer Science

University of Leicester, 2004

Experience

Parachute | Co-founder

2016 — Present | https://www.parachute.io | https://cardsagainstagility.com

Product-focused founder of a small software product consultancy. Our work includes a mix of working with clients to support their product development goals, and building products and businesses of our own.

Example engagements:

CooperVision: Contact Lens Coach

The conversion funnel for new contact lens trialists showed significant drop out in the days after a patient's initial appointment. Our client asked us to consider how we might use technology to improve this.

- Worked directly with opticians to map process and touch points
- Led process of interviewing new lens wearers to understand the practical and emotional factors behind giving up on lenses
- Used this insight to prototype a messaging platform that delivered appropriate support and information to the patient just at the point they were struggling
- · Rapidly tested variations of content, timing and tone of messaging

- Saw a 30% improvement in retention at day 30, with those patients also more likely to commit to a lens subscription service from their optician
- The service was ultimately scaled to serve over 300 UK practices, with plans for rolling out internationally

Estatesearch

This startup saw an opportunity to use newly accessible credit data from Experian to discover the credits and liabilities of an estate during the probate process.

- Assessed new APIs to produce technical specifications matching business needs
- Worked with the development team to prototype an implementation, build against test cases and adjust quickly to what we learned
- Ensured software complied with relevant financial data regulations
- · Helped the client to secure their first customers
- The platform went on to win a number of industry awards and is now profitable

Findmypast: British Newspaper Archive

The BNA had been experiencing a persistent downward trend in subscriber numbers. The leadership team were split on whether to continue investment or begin the process of retiring the consumer-facing product. I was initially tasked with understanding the current situation and supporting them to reach a consensus.

- Undertook extensive qualitative research and analysed historic customer data
- Applied a 'jobs to be done' approach to interpret and present customer needs and behaviours
- Led a small, cross functional team to quickly deliver highly targeted UX and messaging improvements
- Increased conversion of new visitors to a trial by 3x, subsequently increasing MRR by supporting these new customer types into paid memberships
- Advised the leadership team on future opportunities to grow revenue further with a new commercial model
- Asked by the CEO to carry out further assessments of Findmypast portfolio products and approaches to Product Management across the company

Jack Wills

The newly installed e-commerce Director saw difficulty in shipping product improvements; changes were slow to happen and seemed mis-aligned with the wider business strategy. He asked us to discover why and recommend improvements.

- · Mapped the full product process from idea to delivery, making areas of friction visible
- Carried out a skills assessment of the wider team, making training and recruitment recommendations
- Assessed the suitability of third party suppliers and recommended changes to contracts and working agreements
- Supported Jack Wills with the hiring of a full-time Product Manager, at that time a new role for the business

 The ability of the business to ship changes in line with a coherent strategy was vastly improved

Alliants | Senior Consultant (Agile & Lean Product Development) 2014 — 2016

Leading product management engagements with a mix of clients, from £1bn e-commerce platforms, to pre-revenue startups. Also spent significant time teaching and coaching client teams in product management and product delivery. Examples of typical engagements include:

Marks & Spencer | Product Manager

M&S were observing behaviour changes in younger lingerie customers and as a result a large customer demographic was not taking advantage of fitting services. An initial piece of strategy work identified an opportunity to explore the possibility of customers self-serving.

Led the development of a prototype to test and refine the concept, before taking it into production.

- Achieved 94% accuracy in determining correct bra size when compared with a fitting in store
- Conversion for those using the online tool was 150% higher than those on standard online shopping journeys
- · Achieved improvement in units sold per transaction and return rate

Marks & Spencer | Agile Product Coach

Following the success of the lingerie tool, I was invited to build a coaching function, working closely with the leadership team to transform M&S Digital from a top-down, requirements—driven approach into a collection of autonomous product teams.

- Coached and mentored Product Managers and teams across specialisms such as mobile, in-store technology and checkout
- · Created a role definition and career path for the newly-created role of Product Manager
- Guided the organisation in the use of metrics to support effective prioritisation
- Implemented OKRs across M&S Digital to guide organisation structure and appropriate goals
- Reduced release cycle from 60+ to 14 days
- Evangelised a lean, product-led culture throughout the organisation, beyond the scope of the online business
- · Advised Executive Directors and Senior Management on org and team structure
- · Trained and coached scrum masters and agile coaches
- Brought together development, marketing and trading to produce a single, coherent product vision
- Senior stakeholder management in the context of product strategy and prioritisation

Following a significant funding round, I was introduced to Cake to review product strategy and delivery methods. In eight weeks, I was able to refine product decision making in the context of business goals, and help the development team significantly improve quality through a combination of devops and agile delivery.

Channel 5 | Product Manager

Ran an outsourced delivery team for channel5.com. Working closely with Channel 5's stakeholders to understand business priorities and translate these into prioritised, deliverable work items. During the early phase of this engagement, I was able to carefully balance fixing urgent security issues on the platform while continuing to deliver new capabilities during a commercially sensitive period for the organisation.

House Trip | Product Manager

Worked with VP of Growth to improve outcomes from advertising investment. Working with one developer, in four weeks we were able to deliver a functional application that allowed the in-house team to reframe a problem they were struggling to understand, and refine the solution.

- · Rapid prototype of a Rails application
- Iterative development of the solution to deliver maximum value from a very limited budget
- Presentation of findings to guide advertising investment strategy
- · Product roadmap support

Alliants | Development Manager

2011 - 2014

Joining as the third hire in a newly formed development team, I led the implementation of agile methods into Alliants' software offering. Alongside the lead developer, I grew the team to sixteen whilst maintaining a strong product and engineering culture.

Five by Five | Developer

2006 - 2010

Progressing from a junior graduate developer to leading both the technical implementation and team management aspects of projects. Becoming frustrated with the shape of the delivery process, I was able to gather senior-level support and introduce agile practices to our workflow.